Finding Aid for the Mischa Schneider Collection of Test Pressing Recordings, circa 1940-1980
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
Mischa Schneider Collection of Test Pressing Recordings, circa 1940-1980
Mus. Arc. 64
Schneider, Mischa, 1903-1985
2 boxes ( 51 12-inch sound recordings, 1 linear foot, 1 folder )
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
The Mischa Schneider Collection of Test Pressing Recordings contains fifty-one sound recordings on 12-inch discs. The content includes eighteen recordings of performances by the Budapest String Quartet and twelve recordings issued by the Marlboro Recording Society.
Administrative Information
Terms of Access
Materials can be examined by qualified researchers in the Music Library during hours of operation during which Music Librarians are present. In order to insure access, researchers are advised to contact the Music Library in advance of visits.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the estate of Mischa Schneider.
Accruals and Additions
No further accruals are expected to this collection.
Biographical Note
Mischa Schneider (Mojzesz Sznejder) was born in Vilnius, Lithuania February 5 1904 (stated as 1903 in some sources and in the authorized form of his name). He studied cello with Julius Klengel in Leipzig and in Paris with Diran Alexanian. In 1930 he became the cellist with the Budapest Quartet. The group was established around 1917 by the original members, Emil Hauser, Imre Poganyi, Istvan Ipolyi and Harry Son. Mischa was joined in the quartet by his brother Alexander in 1932. Eventually the personnel of the group stabilized as Josef Roisman, first violin, Alexander Schneider, 2nd violin, Boris Kroyt, viola, and Mischa Schneider, cello. Mischa Schneider's last performance with the quartet was in 1965. He continued teaching but never performed again. He died in Buffalo, New York October 3 1985.
Scope and Content Note
The Mischa Schneider Collection of Test Pressing Recordings contains fifty-one sound recordings on 12-inch discs. The content includes eighteen recordings of performances by the Budapest String Quartet and twelve recordings issued by the Marlboro Recording Society. Some of the test pressings bear dates but it is not clear if the dates indicate date of the pressing or date of the recording. All recordings have been marked as undated in the container list. The collection was one component of a larger collection of recordings donated to the library by the family of Mischa Schneider. It is unclear how the test pressings were identified and separated from the original gift. Some of the recordings seem to be commercial releases rather than true test pressings. These have been left in the collection until further research demonstrates whether or not they are actually test pressings.
Some of the Columbia recordings include annotations on the labels or sleeves that state the name of the engineer for the recording, including Thomas Shepard, Thomas Frost, and Sam Carter. The commercial releases associated with the test pressings have been identified where possible. In some cases it is not clear from the information provided which performance or recording date is represented on a disc. In at least one case no commercial recording of a work by the Budapest String Quartet has been identified.
The collection also includes a portion of a recorded interview between Dr. Luther Evans (the tenth Librarian of Congress, 1945-1953) and Mischa Schneider. The interview contains comments about the association between the Budapest String Quartet and the Library of Congress. It was broadcast April 13 1950 on WQQW-FM. One additional folder contains the only non-audio content, four scripts for the radio program Music in the Air. The program featured Columbia Records recordings and the scripts include mention of some of the recordings in the collection.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in four series:
I. Recordings issued by Columbia Records, including CBS, Sony, and Odyssey
II. Recordings issued by Marlboro Recording Society
III. Recordings issued by other labels and an unpublished recording
IV. Music in the Air scripts
Container List
- Recordings issued by Columbia Records, including CBS, Sony, and Odyssey, circa 1940-1979, I.; Item 1-29
  Arranged in two series:
  I.A. Recordings of the Budapest String Quartet
  I.B. Recordings of other performers
  - Recordings of the Budapest String Quartet, 1940-1965, I.A.; Item 1-18
    Arranged alphabetically by first named composer on the recording.
    - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 01, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (2 sides); Released on: Columbia: ML 5008, 1956? Side 1 matrix: None; Side 2 matrix: none Pressing company: Unknown Date of recording: May 1955 Label: "AL 35982" "Columbia Recording Studios Reference Recording" (Box 1, Item 01)
      Work number: 01_01
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791
      Quartets, strings, K. 590, F major
      Transcribed title: Qt no. 23 in F major
      Performers: Budapest String Quartet
      Work number: 01_02
      Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827
      Quartets, strings, no. 2, op. 18, no. 2, G major
      Transcribed title: Qt no. 2 in G major
    - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 02, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (2 sides); Released on: Columbia: ML 5394/MS 6075, 1959 Side 1 matrix: None; Side 2 matrix: None Pressing company: Unknown Date of recording: November 1958 Label: "AL 35983"; Sleeve: "Sam Carter" "Columbia Recording Studios Reference Recording" (Box 1, Item 02)
      Work number: 02_01
      Quartets, strings, no. 3, op. 18, no. 3, D major
      Transcribed title: Qt no. 3 D major
      Work number: 02_02
      Quartets, strings, no. 10, op. 74, E♭ major
      Transcribed title: Qt. #10 in E flat major
    - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 03, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (2 sides); Released on: Columbia: ML 5873/MS 6473, 1963 Side 1 matrix: None; Side 2 matrix: None Pressing company: Unknown Date of recording: Jan. 1962 Label: "Job 65017 Side I"; Sleeve: "Tom Shepard; Beethoven quartet #1 op. 16" (Box 1, Item 03)
      Work number: 03_01
      Schubert. Franz, 1797-1828
      Quintets, piano, violin, viola, cello, double bass, D. 667, A major. Movement 5
      Transcribed title: Trout last mvt.
      Performers: Budapest String Quartet; Mieczyslaw Horszowski, piano; Julius Levine, bass
      Work number: 03_02
      Quintets, piano, oboe, clarinet, horn, bassoon, op. 16, E♭ major; arranged
      Transcribed title: Quartet
      Performers: Mieczyslaw Horszowski, piano; Joseph Roisman, violin; Boris Kroyt, viola; Mischa Schneider, cello
    - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 04, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (2 sides); Released on: CBS/Sony: SOCU-45, 1975 Side 1 matrix: none; Side 2 matrix: none Pressing company: Unknown Date of recording: November 1959 Label: "AL 33309; BL33309"; "4/1/75"; Sleeve: "Tom Frost/MW" "Columbia Recording Studios Reference Recording" (Box 1, Item 04)
      Work number: 04_01
      Septet, clarinet, bassoon, horn, violin, viola, cello, double bass, op. 20, E♭ major
      Transcribed title: Septet Eb Major
      Performers: Budapest String Quartet (without Alexander Schneider); Julian Levine, double bass; David Oppenheim, clarinet; Eli Carmen, bassoon; John Barrows, horn
    - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 05, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (2 sides); Released on: Columbia: ML 6031/MS 6631, 1964 Side 1 matrix: none; Side 2 matrix: none Pressing company: Transco Date of recording: September 1963 On blank side: "Transco 10 363"; Sleeve: "Job 77086 Side 1"; "Ref. Tom Shepard"; (Box 1, Item 05)
      Work number: 05_01
      Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897
      Quintets, piano, strings, op. 34, F minor. Movement 1-2
      Transcribed title: Piano quintet (from sleeve)
      Performers: Rudolf Serkin, piano; Budapest String Quartet
    - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 06, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (2 sides); Released on: [Columbia]: Unknown, Unknown Side 1 matrix: none; Side 2 matrix: none Pressing company: Unknown Date of recording: unknown Label: "Job 108134"; [Side 1] "23/46"; [Side 2] "14/38 "Mono" "Columbia Recording Studios Reference Recording". A published form of this recording has not been identified. It could be one of seven known recordings made at the Library of Congress. Of those, the October 6 1960 performance with Walter Trampler, viola, and Gregor Piatigorsky, cello, is possible. (Box 1, Item 06)
      Work number: 06_01
      Sextets, violins, violas, cellos, no. 1, op. 18, B♭major
      Transcribed title: String sextet
      Performers: Budapest String Quartet (assumed) with unidentified extra viola and cello players
    - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 07, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (2 sides); Released on: Columbia: ML 6211 (or ML 5143 if the 1955 recording), 1956 Side 1 matrix: XYSM 111542-2; Side 2 matrix: none Pressing company: Transco? Date of recording: November 1964 Original sleeve: Transco, Linden, NJ (Box 1, Item 07)
      Work number: 07_01
      Dvořák, Antonín, 1841-1904
      Quartet, strings, B. 179, F major
      Transcribed title: Qt. in F major
    - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 08, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (Single side only); Released on: Columbia/Odyssey: Y 33315, 1975 Side 1 matrix: none; Side 2 matrix: none Pressing company: Unknown Date of recording: December 1956 Label: "MAL 33315"; "Curzon"; Sleeve: "Frost" "Columbia Recording Studios Reference Recording". Note: pianist identified as Jesús María Sanromá on Odyssey release. (Box 1, Item 08)
      Work number: 08_01
      Franck, César, 1822-1890
      Quintets, piano, strings, op. 45, D major
      Transcribed title: Piano 5
      Performers: Clifford Curzon, piano; Budapest String Quartet
    - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 09, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (Single side only); Released on: CBS/Sony: SOCU-46, 1975 Side 1 matrix: none; Side 2 matrix: none Pressing company: Unknown Date of recording: December 1961 Label: "AL 33308"; "Mono"; "4/1/75". Sleeve: "Tom Frost" "Columbia Recording Studios Reference Recording" (Box 1, Item 09)
      Work number: 09_01
      Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847
      Octet, violins (4), violas, violoncellos, op. 20, E♭ major
      Transcribed title: Octet op. 20
      Performers: Budapest String Quartet; Felix Galimir, Isidor Cohen, violins; Walter Trampler, viola; Benar Heifetz, cello
    - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 10, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (2 sides); Released on: CBS/Sony: SOCU-46, 1975 Side 1 matrix: none; Side 2 matrix: none Pressing company: Unknown Date of recording: December 1961 Label: "Job 108134"; 2/7/75"; Side 7 of 8, Side 8 of 8. Sleeve: "Tom Frost" "Columbia Recording Studios Reference Recording"; this is a recording of a live performance (Box 1, Item 10)
      Work number: 10_01
      Transcribed title: String octet in E flat major op. 20
    - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 11, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (Single side only); Released on: CBS/Sony: SOCU-46, 1975 Side 1 matrix: none; Side 2 matrix: none Pressing company: Unknown Date of recording: December 1961 Label: "BL 33308"; "Mono"; "4/1/75". Sleeve: "Tom Frost" "Columbia Recording Studios Reference Recording" (Box 1, Item 11)
      Work number: 11_01
      Quintets, violins, violas, cello, no. 1, op. 18, A major
      Transcribed title: Quintet in A major
      Performers: Budapest String Quartet; Walter Trampler, viola
    - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 12, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (2 sides); Released on: Columbia: Y3 35240 (Y 35981--Y 35983), 1979 Side 1 matrix: Q010200 (imprint on blank side); Side 2 matrix: none Pressing company: Unknown Date of recording: February 1940? On label: "AL 35981"; Title on label states B flat minor, with minor crossed out "Columbia Recording Studios Reference Recording"; Not positive this is the same recording issued in the Odyssey set but the matrix number matches. (Box 1, Item 12)
      Work number: 12_01
      Quartets, strings, K. 458, B♭major
      Transcribed title: Qt. no. 17 in B flat
    - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 13, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (Single side only); Released on: Columbia: ML 5873/MS 6473, 1963 Side 1 matrix: none; Side 2 matrix: none Pressing company: Unknown Date of recording: January 1962 On sleeve: "Job 65017 Side II"; "Tom Shepard" (Box 1, Item 13)
      Work number: 13_01
      Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828
      Quintets, piano, violin, viola, cello, double bass, D. 667, A major. Movements 1-4
      Transcribed title: Trout Mvts 1, 2, 3, 4
    - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 14, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (2 sides); Released on: Columbia: ML5936/MS 6536, 1964 Side 1 matrix: XXLP75810; Side 2 matrix: XXLP75811 Pressing company: Unknown Date of recording: June 1962 On sleeve: "Att Tom Shepard; Monaural two sides; Schubert string quintet (Box 1, Item 14)
      Work number: 14_01
      Quintets, violins, viola, cellos, D. 956, C major
      Transcribed title: Quintet
      Performers: Budapest String Quartet; Benar Heifetz, cello
    - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 15, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (2 sides); Released on: Columbia: ML5936/MS 6536, 1964 Side 1 matrix: none; Side 2 matrix: none Pressing company: Unknown Date of recording: June 1962 On label: "108134 29/29, 18/39" "Columbia Recording Studios Reference Recording" (Box 1, Item 15)
      Work number: 15_01
      Transcribed title: String quintet
    - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 16, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (Single side only); Released on: Columbia: ML5936/MS 6536, 1964 Side 1 matrix: XXSM 75812 (20965); Side 2 matrix: none Pressing company: Unknown Date of recording: June 1962 On label: "Reference Shepherd"; On sleeve: "stereo" (Box 1, Item 16)
      Work number: 16_01
      Quintets, violins, viola, cellos, D. 956, C major. Movements 1-2
      Transcribed title: Cello 5
    - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 17, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (Single side only); Released on: Columbia: ML5936/MS 6536, 1964 Side 1 matrix: XXSM 78813 (20965); Side 2 matrix: none Pressing company: Unknown Date of recording: June 1962 On label: "Reference Shepherd"; On sleeve: "stereo" (Box 1, Item 17)
      Work number: 17_01
      Quintets, violins, viola, cellos, D. 956, C major. Movements 3-4
    - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 18, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (2 sides); Released on: Columbia: Unknown, Unknown Side 1 matrix: none; Side 2 matrix: none Pressing company: Unknown Date of recording: unknown Label: "4/9/75 Mono N+2 Job 108134"; Sleeve: "Tom Frost, Masterworks" "Columbia Recording Studios Reference Recording". Cannot identify related commercial release. Two recordings were made at the Library of Congress, 1958 and 1960. There is also a 1978 release on Columbia/Odyssey by the Borodin Quartet. (Box 1, Item 18)
      Work number: 18_01
      Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893
      Souvenir de Florence
      Transcribed title: String sextet in D minor, op. 70
      Performers: probably Guarneri Quartet with Mischa Schneider and Boris Kroyt
  - Recordings of the other performers, 1940-1965, I.B.; Item 19-29
    - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 19, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (2 sides); Released on: Columbia: M 35163, 1979 Side 1 matrix: none; Side 2 matrix: none Pressing company: Unknown Date of recording: unknown Label: "AL 35163 Marlboro normal level" "Columbia Reference Recording" (Box 1, Item 19)
      Work number: 19_01
      Hummel, Johann Nepomuk, 1778-1837
      Grand septuor
      Transcribed title: Septet
      Performers: Judith Mendenhall, flute; Rudolph Vrbsky, oboe; Robert Routch, horn; Caroline Levine, viola; Lisa Lancaster, cello; Julius Levine, bass; Beth Levin, piano
      Work number: 19_02
      Boccherini, Luigi, 1743-1805
      Quintets, violins, viola, violoncellos, G. 298, C major
      Transcribed title: Boccherini
      Performers: Pina Carmirelli, Naoko Tanaka, violins; Philipp Naegele, viola; Jerry Grossman, Marcy Rosen, cellos
    - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 20, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (Single side only); Released on: Columbia: M 35163, 1979 Side 1 matrix: none; Side 2 matrix: none Pressing company: Unknown Date of recording: unknown Label: "MBL-35163"; "5-14-79" "Columbia Reference Recording" (Box 1, Item 20)
      Work number: 20_01
      Grand septuor. Movement 4
      Transcribed title: Septet IV Mvmt.
      Work number: 20_02
      Transcribed title: Quintet in C maj. Op. 25 no. 4
    - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 21, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (2 sides); Released on: Columbia: ML 6031/MS 6631, 1964 Side 1 matrix: none; Side 2 matrix: none Pressing company: Transco Date of recording: September 1963 On blank side: "Transco 10 363"; Sleeve: "Job 77086 Side 2"; "Ref. Tom Shepard"; (Box 1, Item 21)
      Work number: 21_01
      Quintets, piano, strings, op. 34, F minor. Movement 3-4
    - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 22, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (2 sides); Released on: Columbia: MS 7207, 1969 Side 1 matrix: none; Side 2 matrix: XXSM138444-2A Pressing company: Pitman Date of recording: unknown (Box 1, Item 22)
      Work number: 22_02
      Partch, Harry, 1901-1974
      Wayward. Barstow
      Transcribed title: Barstow
      Performers: Ensembles of instruments developed by the composer, narration by the composer and John Stannard; Danlee Mitchell, conductor.
      Work number: 22_03
      Plectra and percussion dances. Castor and Pollux
      Transcribed title: Castor and Pollux
      Performers: Ensembles of instruments developed by the composer; Danlee Mitchell, conductor
      Work number: 22_01
      Daphne of the dunes
      Transcribed title: Daphne
      Performers: Ensembles of instruments developed by the composer, narration by the composer and John Stannard; Danlee Mitchell, conductor
    - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 23, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (2 sides); Released on: Columbia: MS 6891, 1966 Side 1 matrix: XTV-91980-2A; Side 2 matrix: XTV-91981-2A Pressing company: Unknown Date of recording: 1963 No indication of Columbia on item (Box 1, Item 23)
      Work number: 23_01
      Reger, Max, 1873-1916
      Sonatas, cello, piano, no. 4, op. 116, A minor
      Transcribed title: As performed at the Marlboro Music Festival 1963: Cello sonata in A minor, op. 116
      Performers: Mischa Schneider, cello; Peter Serkin, piano
    - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 24, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (2 sides); Released on: Columbia: MS 6891, 1966 Side 1 matrix: XTV-91980-2A; Side 2 matrix: XTV-91981-2A Pressing company: Unknown Date of recording: 1963 No indication of Columbia on item (Box 1, Item 24)
      Work number: 24_01
    - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 25, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (2 sides); Released on: Columbia: MS 6891, 1966 Side 1 matrix: XTV-91980-2A; Side 2 matrix: XTV-91981-2A Pressing company: Unknown Date of recording: 1963 No indication of Columbia on item (Box 1, Item 25)
      Work number: 25_01
    - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 26, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (Single side only); Released on: Columbia: ML 6291, 1966 Side 1 matrix: none; Side 2 matrix: none Pressing company: Unknown Date of recording: unknown Label: "Att Mr Tom Shepard 10-23-63, Job 77086, Mono." "Columbia Reference Recording" (Box 1, Item 26)
      Work number: 26_01
      Sonatas, cello, piano, no. 4, op. 116, A minor. Movement 1-2
      Transcribed title: Cello sonata Part 1
    - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 27, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (Single side only); Released on: Columbia: ML 6291, 1966 Side 1 matrix: none; Side 2 matrix: none Pressing company: Unknown Date of recording: unknown Label: "Att Tom Shepard 10-23-63, Job 77086" "Columbia Reference Recording" (Box 1, Item 27)
      Work number: 27_01
      Sonatas, cello, piano, no. 4, op. 116, A minor. Movement 3-4
      Transcribed title: Cello sonata Part 2
    - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 28, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (2 sides); Released on: Columbia: ML 4488, 1956? Side 1 matrix: FXLP 6991; Side 2 matrix: XLP 6992 Pressing company: Unknown Date of recording: unknown Looks like commercial release rather than test pressing. (Box 1, Item 28)
      Work number: 28_01
      Rodgers, Richard, 1902-1979
      Babes in arms. Selections; arr.
      Transcribed title: Babes in arms
      Performers: Mary Martin, Mardi Bayne and Jack Cassidy, vocals; Lehman Engel, conductor; various arrangers
    - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 29, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (2 sides); Released on: Columbia: ML 4487, 1953 Side 1 matrix: XLP 9012; Side 2 matrix: XLP 9013 Pressing company: Unknown Date of recording: unknown Originally a piano suite; arr. for piano and orchestra. Looks like the commercial release rather than a test pressing. (Box 1, Item 29)
      Work number: 29_01
      Vremena goda; arr.
      Transcribed title: The months, op. 37a
      Performers: Morton Gould Orchestra, Morton Gould piano and conductor
- Recordings issued by Marlboro Recording Society, circa 1970-1980, II.; Item 30-45
  Arranged in numerical order by Marlboro Recording Society publisher number.
  - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 30, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (2 sides); Released on: Marlboro Recording Society: MRS-1, 1970? Side 1 matrix: MRS 1A-1B; Side 2 matrix: none Pressing company: Unknown Date of recording: 1968? Final movement (Rondo) on Side 2 (Box 1, Item 30)
    Work number: 30_01
    Serenades, orchestra, no. 2, op. 16, A major
    Transcribed title: Serenade in A major, op. 16
    Performers: Marlboro Festival Orchestra; Pablo Casals, conductor
    Work number: 30_02
    Sonatas, violin, piano, K. 13, F major
    Transcribed title: Sonata in F major, K. 13
    Performers: Pina Carmirelli, violin; David Cole, cello; Rudolf Serkin, piano
    Work number: 30_03
    Sonatas, violin, piano, K. 12, A major
    Transcribed title: Sonata in A major, K. 12
  - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 31, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (2 sides); Released on: Marlboro Recording Society: MRS-2, 1970? Side 1 matrix: MRS-2-A; 38095-A; Side 2 matrix: none Pressing company: Unknown Date of recording: 1966 or 1967 AL Printed labels loose; beneath them is a symbol like two interlocked M's. The remainder of the Suite (the Gigue) opens Side 2 of the disc. (Box 1, Item 31)
    Work number: 31_01
    Schoenberg, Arnold, 1874-1951
    Suites, piano, clarinets (3), strings, op. 29
    Transcribed title: Suite. Op. 29: Overture/Tanzschritte, Thema mit Variationen, Gigue
    Performers: James Corwin, Harold Wright, Don Stewart, clarinets; Jamie Laredo, violin; Samuel Rhodes, viola; Madeline Foley, cello; Ruth Laredo, piano; Leon Kirchner, conductor
    Work number: 31_02
    Quintets, violins, viola, violoncellos, G. 348, F minor
    Transcribed title: Quintet in F major, op. 42, no. 1
    Performers: Pina Carmirelli, Jon Toth, violins; Philipp Naegele, viola; Fortunato Arico, Dorothy Reichenberger, cellos
  - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 32, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (2 sides); Released on: Marlboro Recording Society: MRS-3, 1970-1979 Side 1 matrix: MRS 3A (34276); Side 2 matrix: none Pressing company: Unknown Date of recording: unknown Serenade completed on Side 2. (Box 1, Item 32)
    Work number: 32_01
    Serenades, bass, instrumental ensemble, op. 24
    Transcribed title: Serenade op. 24
    Performers: Thomas Paul, bass; Harold Wright, clarinet; Don Stewart, bass clarinet; Stanley Silverman, guitar; Jacob Glick, mandolin; Leon Kirchner, conductor
    Work number: 32_02
    Introduction et variations sur un thème original